本字幕由YYeTs人人影视翻译制作
更多美剧字幕 请登陆 www.YYeTs.net
■
《反恐24小时》前情提要
Previously on 24
你在找谁
Who is it you're looking for?
一个能告诉我所有涉案人员名单的人
Someone who can give me the names of everyone else involved.
如果我死了  我要你把真相公之于众
I need you to break the story in case I don't make it.
如果让达莉亚·哈桑发觉
If Dalia Hassan finds out
俄罗斯人跟她丈夫的死脱不了干系
that the Russians had a hand in the death of her husband,
她决不会签署协议的
she'll never sign the agreement.
我需要跟你母亲通话
I need to speak to your mother.
此事关系到谋杀令尊的真凶
It's about the people who really murdered your father.
我们知道凶手是谁
We know who is responsible.
但你不知道
What you don't know is,
这些凶手听命于一群俄罗斯间谍
those people were working under the orders of Russian agents.
鲍尔跟梅瑞狄斯·里德取得了联络
Bauer made contact with Meredith Reed.
-天哪  -您必须给她的出版商打电话
- My God. - You need to call her publisher
并要求他们不要报道此事
and demand that they do not run the story.
你在建议我封住媒体的嘴吗
You're suggesting muzzling the press?
如果您不动用白宫的力量
If you don't use the power of your office
阻止此事见报
to shut this story down,
损失的将不止是您的和平进程
your peace agreement won't be the only casualty.
我需要你与联邦调查局取得联系
I need you to contact the FBI.
让他们找到里德
Have them locate Reed
并截获她声称拥有的任何证据
and seize whatever evidence she purports to have.
梅瑞狄斯·里德  联邦调查局
Meredith Reed? FBI.
你被逮捕了
You're under arrest.
-我们走吧  -但我...
- Let's go. - But I...
你说的没错
You were right about Jack.
确实有人在帮助杰克
He is working with somebody.
是詹姆斯·理查尔  前中情局情报特工
It's James Ricker, ex-CIA Op.
我们已经找到他在梅瑟大街的住所
We found him living in a place on Mercer Street.
被我们挖出来  他一定不会高兴的
He's not gonna be happy we tracked him down.
我要你去跟他谈谈
I need you to talk to him.
让他说出杰克的下落
Get him to tell us where Jack is.
你能处理好吗  或者你还没想好该站哪边
Are you good with that, or have you still not taken sides?
我跟你一样想让真相大白于天下  算上我
I want to expose this cover-up as much as you. I'm in.
那是杰克·鲍尔
That's Jack Bauer!
给我起来  否则我就地宰了你
Get up. I could just kill you right here.
你知道那个俄罗斯政府内部
You know the name of the person inside
负责此事的人的名字
the Russian government who's giving the orders.
告诉我那个名字
I want that name.
-杰克  -快告诉我名字
- Jack...  - Give me the name!
我说  我说
I'll tell you.
-4  3...  -是米哈伊尔·诺瓦科维奇
- Four. Three... - Mikhail Novakovich!
诺瓦科维奇在哪
Where's Novakovich?
他死了
He's dead.
鲍尔进来就开枪
Bauer just came in shooting.
米哈伊尔·诺瓦科维奇刚被杰克·鲍尔给杀了
Mikhail Novakovich was just murdered by Jack Bauer.
什么
What?
对鲍尔来说
As far as, uh, bauer is concerned,
做了诺瓦科维奇就完事了
the trail ended with Novakovich.
那么  鲍尔还不知道
Then Bauer has no idea
诺瓦科维奇是遵从我的命令行事的  对吗
that Novakovich was operating under my orders?
是的
None.
如果你这么担心鲍尔的话
If you're so worried about Bauer,
就不应该下令杀掉蕾妮·沃克
you never should have given the order to kill Renee Walker.
以下事件发生于下午两点到三点间
The following takes place between 2:00 P.M. and 3:00 P.M.
事件实时发生
Events occur in real time.
阿洛
Arlo.
科尔  我刚得到一条初步的信息
Cole, I just picked up a preliminary flash.
杰克在诺瓦克维奇下榻的酒店里杀了他
Jack murdered Novakovich at his hotel,
以及他的六个保镖
and six of his security guards.
据一名目击者称
According to a witness,
杰克以一己之力做掉七人
Jack killed all seven men on his own.
然后就此从我们的视野里消失了
Then fell right back off the radar.
伊登找不到他的任何踪迹
Eden can't find any trace of him.
克罗伊知道这事吗
Does Chloe know about this?
我刚向她报告了此事
I just talked to her,
她应该马上就到联合国总部了
and she should be at the U.N. any minute.
科尔  我知道我们必须拿到杰克手上的证据
Cole, I know that we need this evidence that Jack has,
但这个凶案现场形同屠宰场
but this crime scene is a slaughterhouse.
克罗伊还坚持认为她能成功阻止事态发展吗
Does Chloe really still think she can pull this off?
如果还有人能说服杰克  那就只有克罗伊了
If anyone can talk Jack down, it's Chloe.
如果她办不到呢
And if she can't?
那我俩就得做好准备  不惜一切阻止他了
Then we're both prepared to do whatever it takes to stop him.
可连诺瓦科维奇那些保镖也阻止不了他
Even when Novakovich's whole security staff couldn't?
你还有什么好办法吗  阿洛
What do you want me to do, Arlo?
今天事件的真相得大白于天下
The truth about what went down today needs to get out,
但找不到杰克  一切都是枉然
and that's not going to happen unless we get to Jack.
我快到理查尔的公寓了
Look, I'm coming up on Ricker's apartment.
我准备硬闯了
I'm going in.
-科尔  -怎么了
- Cole. - What?
理查尔费尽周折才掩盖掉自己的行踪
Ricker went to a lot of trouble to disappear.
被你挖出来  他不会很高兴的
He's not going to like that you found him.
我也没指望他欢迎我
I'm not expecting him to.
您现在看到的是联合国广场花园以及演讲台
You're looking at the U.N. Plaza gardens and the podium
在那里签署和平协议的三方签署国
from which all three co-sponsors
在公开演讲结束后
of the peace treaty will address the public
各方将在联合国会议中心举行
following a private signing ceremony inside the U.N.'s
和平协议的签署仪式
Council Chamber.
俄罗斯总统尤里·萨瓦洛夫
Russian President Yuri Suvarov,
协议的第三方签署国
the third co-sponsor of the treaty,
正在前往联合国总部的途中
is en route to the U.N.
在那里  他将和泰勒总统
where he will join President Taylor
以及伊斯兰共和国代理总统达莉亚·哈桑一起...
and acting IRK President Dalia Hassan...
安全警报
翻译： hodala     猫太郎     叶eve     罗玉凤     非燕
■
时间轴：何何     佐佐     水水     泡泡龙     艾田
校对：何何     非燕     aiai     无辜     插线     罗玉凤
■
后期：冰河     特别鸣谢：咖啡   Nil     监制：何何
启动全球系统清除程序
Initiate GlobalSystem Wipe
理查尔先生  我是反恐小组的奥迪斯
Mr. Ricker, this is Agent Ortiz, CTU!
把门打开
Open that door.
在你开枪前
Before you pull that trigger,
你得知道些情况
there's something you ought to know.
如果我十五分钟内不打电话报告
I don't place a call in 15 minutes,
国内各个情报机构都将收到关于你的警报
every intelligence agency in the country gets alerted about you.
光被控军火交易就会让你在牢里待很长一段时间
Weapon charges alone will get you locked up for the duration,
或者你可以帮我们找到杰克·鲍尔
Or you can help us find Jack Bauer,
我们会对你的存在守口如瓶
and we'll keep our mouths shut.
你觉得自己是在保护他吗
You think you're protecting him?
对杰克·鲍尔的命令是格杀勿论
The order on Jack Bauer is shoot to kill.
他知道自己正惹上什么麻烦
He knew what he was getting himself into.
现在的杰克头脑并不清醒
Jack's not thinking straight.
我看过你的档案
Look, I read your file.
我知道杰克曾在大马士革救过你一命
I know Jack saved your life in Damascus.
而现在正是你报答他的时候
This is your opportunity to pay back that debt.
你知道这事会怎么收场  对吧
You know how this is gonna end, right?
如果今天杰克死了  都是你的错
If Jack dies today, it's on you.
等等
Wait a minute.
留步
谢谢  亚当
Thanks, Adam.
已被逮捕
Arrested
奥布赖恩主管  我是伯克探员
Director O'Brian, Agent Burke.
这里有一份修订后的安全评估给你
I have the revised security assessment for you.
长官  我注意到奥迪斯探员的名字
Ma'am, I noticed that Agent Ortiz's name
-出现在轮值表中  -没错
- was back on the duty roster. - That's right.
他不是因协助杰克·鲍尔被逮捕了吗
He was arrested for helping Jack Bauer.
他已获临时豁免来此协助我们工作
I got him a temporary clearance so he could help us out here.
他当初是设计联合国安保部署的主要负责人
He was the one who designed the U.N. protocols in the first place.
我们真的可以信任他吗
Do you really think we can trust him?
我不信任他就不会放他出来了
I wouldn't have gotten him a release if I didn't.
-明白  长官  -失陪了
- Yes, ma'am. - Excuse me.
-怎么了  -情况不妙  克罗伊
- What happened? - Not good, Chloe.
我觉得杰克正冲着萨瓦洛夫去了
I think Jack's targeting Suvarov.
-是理查尔说的吗  -是的
- Is that what Ricker said? - Yeah.
杰克在查尔斯·罗根身上放了个窃听器
Jack planted a bug on Charles Logan,
偷听到了他们俩的对话
overheard a conversation between the two men.
原来是萨瓦洛夫下令杀死蕾妮的
Turns out Suvarov's the one who gave the order for Renee to be killed.
理查尔有没有那次对话的录音
Does Ricker have a recording of that conversation?
没有  他一看见我过来
No. He wiped his system clean
就清空了系统
as soon as he saw me coming.
但他给杰克的监视设备录下了一切  作为备份
But the surveillance rig he gave Jack records everything to a backup,
所以杰克有一个副本
so Jack has a copy.
很好  我们会用到它的
Good. We're gonna need it.
白宫刚刚拘捕了梅瑞狄斯·里德
The White House just arrested Meredith Reed.
没收了她的数据卡
They confiscated a data card from her.
就是丹娜的证据
Dana's evidence.
没错  杰克现在手里的那份录音
Exactly. The recording that Jack has
是我们手里的唯一一份证据了
is the only proof we have now.
获取证据是我们的首要任务
that getting proof is our first priority anymore.
我们得发布一条关于杰克的警报
We have to put an alert out on Jack.
如果我们那么做的话  皮勒就会先下手
If we do that, then Pillar will get to him first.
他会杀了杰克  然后再毁掉录音
He'll kill Jack, and he'll destroy the recording.
克罗伊  我们不能就这么袖手旁观
Chloe, we can't stand by
任凭杰克刺杀俄罗斯总统
and let Jack assassinate the president of Russia.
当然不能  但是我们可以争取到时间
No, but we can buy ourselves time.
可以改变萨瓦洛夫的车队行驶路线
Can change Suvarov's motorcade route,
让他隐蔽在联合国总部内
sequester him in the U.N.
不给杰克得手的机会
Make it impossible for Jack to get to him.
只是萨瓦洛夫很快就要上演讲台了
Yeah, except Suvarov's gonna be standing at that podium soon,
而且一旦他的目标那么明显
and once he's exposed like that,
我们就没办法保护他了
we can't protect him.
还要一个多小时呢
That's not happening for over an hour.
如果到时候我们还没找到杰克
If we haven't found Jack by then,
那我们就可以发出警报了
then we can put out the alert.
这还是在冒很大的风险  克罗伊
It's still taking a big risk, Chloe.
好吧  改变萨瓦洛夫的行进路线
All right, get Suvarov's route changed.
但是他一到联合国总部
But you're putting me in charge of his security
你必须让我负责他的安全
as soon as he gets to the U.N.
你还有多远
How far out are you?
十分钟后到
I'll be there in ten.
好的
Okay.
长官  诺瓦科维奇的报道就要播出了
Sir, the flash about Novakovich is going out.
你说过你想在那之前要和总统谈谈
You wanted to speak with the president before that happened.
谢谢  杰森
Thank you, Jason.
有鲍尔的消息了吗
Do we know anything about Bauer?
没有
No. Nothing.
长官  如果您不介意我问个问题的话
If you don't mind me asking, sir.
您打算和总统怎么说
What are you going to tell the president?
我想是时候向总统坦白一切了
I think it's time she... she knows everything.
除了还在途中的萨瓦洛夫之外
All the delegates are present with the exception of Suvarov,
所有的代表都到了
who's still in transit.
他到之后就会马上告诉他详细的会议流程
He'll be given the details once he arrives.
等一下  蒂姆
Excuse me, Tim.
是  总统阁下
Yes, ma'am.
我马上就要开准备会了
I'm about to go into the protocol meeting.
出什么事了
What's going on?
我想让您先从我这里听说这条消息
I wanted you to hear this news from me first.
什么消息
What news?
我一直尽全力  让您与此事没有瓜葛
I tried to insulate you as long as I could,
保住您有推诿责任的余地  可...
preserve your plausible deniability, but...
你到底想要说什么  查尔斯
Just tell me what you're talking about, Charles.
杰克·鲍尔不只在
Jack Bauer isn't just trying to
搜集这次阴谋的证据
gather evidence about the conspiracy.
他要复仇
He's seeking retribution.
继续
Go on.
鲍尔刚谋杀了米哈伊尔·诺瓦科维奇
Bauer just murdered Mikhail Novakovich,
及其众多手下
along with a good number of his staff.
那诺瓦科维奇是刺杀哈桑总统的幕后黑手吗
So Novakovich was responsible for the assassination of President Hassan?
是的  阁下
Yes. Yes, ma'am.
诺瓦科维奇是俄罗斯代表团的高级官员
Novakovich was the ranking member of the Russian Delegation.
萨瓦洛夫总统会要求给出解释
President Suvarov is going to demand an explanation.
实际上  他不会
Actually, he's not.
难道你想告诉我
Are you telling me
谋杀哈桑全都是萨瓦洛夫指使的吗
that Hassan's murder goes all the way up to Suvarov?
是的
Yes.
不过好消息是鲍尔还不知道这件事
But the good news is that Bauer doesn't know that.
你怎么能这么肯定
How can you be sure?
因为据一名目击者称
Because according to a witness,
鲍尔在诺瓦科维奇开口说话前
Bauer killed Novakovich
就把他杀了
before he could talk.
除了我以外
And aside from me,
诺瓦科维奇是唯一一个知道
Novakavich is the only person who ever knew
萨瓦洛夫是幕后黑手的人
that Suvarov was calling the shots.
总统阁下  鲍尔已经达到了他的目的
Madam President, Bauer's finished what he started,
萨瓦洛夫也会很高兴解决了这个烫手的山芋
an-and Suvarov will be happy to sweep this under the rug.
和平协议可以按原计划进行下去了
An-and the peace agreement can go forward as planned.
这...
This is...
真的  我们不能再奢求更好的结果了
Really, we couldn't have asked for a better outcome.
只是我要求达莉亚·哈桑和他的杀夫凶手握手
Except that I am asking Dalia Hassan to shake hands with her husband's murderer.
给萨瓦洛夫打电话
Call Suvarov.
告诉他我已经知道了他参与了这个阴谋
Tell him that I am aware of his involvement in this,
我会在签署仪式上和他见面
and that I will see him at the signing.
非常抱歉
My apologies.
让大家久等了
Thank you for waiting.
-电话怎么说的  -我已经告诉总统
- How did the call go? - I told the president
萨瓦洛夫也参与其中
about Suvarov's involvement, and, um...
而她也明白  自己没有别的选择
she understood-- not that she has an alternative.
是个好消息  长官
Well, that's good news, sir.
您的新特勤局侍卫队已经到了
Your new Secret Service detail's here
他们会护送您到联合国总部
to escort you to the U.N.
谢谢  杰森
Thank you, Jason.
长路漫漫  不过...
It's been a long road, but, uh...
曙光就在眼前
we're almost there.
有鲍尔的最新消息吗
Anything new on Bauer?
一个监控探头拍到了他离开诺瓦科维奇下榻的酒店
A security camera picked him up leaving Novakovich's hotel.
证实了伯科夫所说的
Confirmed what Berkov told us.
鲍尔在攻击时确实受伤了
Bauer was definitely wounded during the attack.
多严重
How badly?
严重到他需要接受治疗
Badly enough that he's gonna need treatment.
正在向医疗机构发布警报
Getting alerts out to medical facilities now.
好的  也让港务局和移民局知道
All right, also let Port Authority and INS know
鲍尔可能试图逃到国外去
Bauer might be trying to get out of the country.
我们会找到他的  这只不过是时间问题
We'll find him-- It's only a question of time.
也许会比你预想的还要快
Maybe a little quicker than you thought.
慢慢地拿出你的枪  递给我
Slowly, take your weapon out and pass it back to me.
慢点
Slowly.
开车
Start the car and drive.
你看见我对帕维尔做了什么了
You saw what I did to Pavel.
我没有太多时间和他纠缠
I didn't have a lot of time with him.
至于你  我有的是时间
You, I've got all the time in the world.
所以你要么照我说的做  要么我将你大卸八块
So you either do what I say, or I will take you apart piece by piece.
开车
Now, drive!
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
联合国总部
The U.N.
为什么去那  你已经得到你想要的了
Why? You already got what you wanted.
你杀了所有有牵连的人
You killed everyone involved.
别废话了
Save your breath.
我知道萨瓦洛夫总统也参与了
I know about President Suvarov.
您的代表团会在签署仪式结束后
Your delegations will be joining you at the reception
在招待会与您回合
after the post-signing ceremony.
最后  我谨代表联合国工作人员
And finally, on behalf of the U.N. Staff,
想说的是  能见证这一历史时刻
I would like to say that we are all honored
我们所有成员都感到非常荣幸
to be part of this historic occasion.
感谢各位的聆听
Thank you for your time.
您的女儿一直在外面等着  有事要对您说
Your daughter's been waiting outside to speak to you.
她说事关重大
She says it's important.
-告诉她我马上去找她  -是  阁下
- Let her know I'll be right there. - Yes, ma'am.
总统阁下
Madam President.
我有东西要给您
I have something for you.
是奥马赠送的
It's from Omar.
他原本打算在签署协议的时候给您用的
He wanted to give it to you to sign the agreement, and...
有幸我能代表他转交给您
I'm grateful that I can do so on his behalf.
上面写道  "所有的宗教信仰
It reads "All religions,
"一切的歌颂
"All this singing,
"皆为一愿
"One song,
愿真主[和平]与您同在" [双关语]
peace be with you."
当奥马谈到你们共同为之奋斗的事业时
It is a verse Omar would quote from Rumi
他总会引用鲁米的这首诗
when he was talking about what you and he were trying to achieve.
感谢您同我们一起共度难关
Thank you for seeing this through
并感谢您帮助我们重新认识了哈桑
and for helping us all do justice to his memory.
达莉亚  我...
Dalia, I am...
这是我的荣幸
I am honored.
我倍感荣幸
I'm very honored.
凯拉  怎么了
Kayla, what is it?
梅瑞狄斯·里德打过电话到您的住所找您
Meredith Reed called the residence looking for you.
我不想听那女人所谓的慰问
I am not interested in that woman's condolences.
她不是为这个打电话来的
That is not why she called.
她说她有杀害父亲幕后凶手的情报
She says she has information about the people who are behind father's murder.
但我们都知道谁是幕后凶手了
But we know who was behind your father's death--
是我们国家的极端主义分子
extremists in our country.
她声称他们有外国势力协助
She claims that they had outside help.
是俄罗斯人
That the Russians were involved.
她为什么会说这些
Why would she say such a thing?
她有证据吗  还是只是谣言
Does she have evidence, or is this just a rumor?
我不知道  但她也不会草率打电话给您的
I don't know, but it can't have been easy for her to call you.
我认为她不会因为一个谣言就来告诉我们
I don't think she would have done so because of a rumor.
她还说了什么
What else did she say?
在和您讲上话之前  她不愿再透露更多
She wouldn't say anything more until she talked to you.
她留了她的电话号码
She left her number.
我们回住所给她打电话
Let's call her from the residence.
安  萨瓦洛夫总统的车队因为路线改变
Ann, President Suvarov's motorcade is delayed
要晚五分钟  把这通知所有机构
five minutes because of the new route-- put out an all-agency.
机密等级如何设置
How do you want it coded?
绝密
Eyes only.
是  长官
Yes, ma'am.
兰扎  确保伯克到这里报告的时候
Lanza, make sure Burke reports here
给奥迪斯探员带套战术装备
with a set of tactical gear for Agent Ortiz.
是  长官
Yes, ma'am.
阿洛正在反恐组用面部识别软件
Arlo's at CTU, running the surveillance video
扫描监控录像
through facial recognition software.
-还是没有发现杰克  -我一直在想
- Still no sign of Jack. - Look, I've been thinking.
假如我们确实从杰克那里拿到了这个录音
Let's say we do get this recording from Jack.
我们要怎么处理它
What are we supposed to do with it?
我是说  总统既然决心扣押梅瑞狄斯...
I mean, if the president's willing to lock down Meredith Reed...
但她无法封上全球所有媒体的嘴
She can't shut down every media outlet in the world,
这意味着我们能把证据传出去
which is where we're gonna send this file.
我们还要把证据发给国内所有政府部门的公务员
We're also gonna send it to every government employee in the country.
包括立法机构  军方  以及司法部
Legislative, military, judiciary--
那就是十万多人
that's over a hundred thousand people.
我们怎么才能做到
How are we doing this?
通过反恐组的服务器
By using CTU servers,
我们能够把证据同时发给所有人
we can distribute it simultaneously to everyone.
真相终会大白  就算是泰勒总统也拦不住
President Taylor won't be able to stop the truth from getting out.
伯克
Burke.
-很高兴见到你  -长官
- Good to see you. - Sir.
你用了萨瓦洛夫总统到达路线的修改方案吗
Did you use the revised protocol for President Suvarov's arrival?
是的  长官
Yes, ma'am.
我们正让车队行驶到罗斯福大道的匝道上去
We're now bringing the motorcade into the FDR Drive ramp.
很好
Good.
确保奥迪斯探员拿到车队路线的修改方案
Make sure that Agent Ortiz has the revised protocols.
他已恢复外勤指挥权
He's back in charge.
去看看情况吧
Let's take a look.
我们要开到哈特大厦
We're going to the Hart Building.
我要你把车停到地下停车场
I want you to park underground.
这个守卫的命掌握在你手里
This guard's life is in your hands.
你敢乱来  我就杀了你们两个  明白吗
You make one move that I don't like, I'm gonna kill you both, you understand?
杰森·皮勒
Jason Pillar.
里面没人
There's no one inside.
他们在两小时前离开了大厦
They left the building two hours ago.
我只是进行最后的安检工作
Yeah, I'm just running a last-minute security check.
遵命  长官
Of course, sir.
还有什么问题吗  长官
Is there anything else, sir?
没有  谢谢
No. Thank you.
开车
Drive.
就在这停车
Pull in over here.
慢慢地  用你的右手
Slowly, with your right hand,
把车钥匙拔出来
take the keys out of the ignition
然后递给我
and pass them back.
下车
Get out of the car.
快点
Now!
关门
Close the door.
把手放在车顶上
Put your hands on the roof.
不许动
Don't you move.
萨瓦洛夫要再过一小时才会出现在演讲台上
Suvarov's not gonna be out on the podium for another hour.
按你流血的速度
You're not gonna make it that long,
你撑不到那个时候
not the way you're bleeding.
慢慢地
Slowly,
背着走向我
back up towards me.
停下  转过来
Stop. Turn around.
好
Good.
你帮我缝合伤口
You're gonna suture me up.
你要敢对我乱来
You try and make a move on me,
哪怕是很小的动作
the slightest twitch,
我就一枪崩了你
I will put a bullet in your brain.
你明白吗
You got it?
明白
Yes.
我有点不明白
I don't understand something.
你的整个职业生涯都在干着出格的事
You've spent your entire career working outside the system;
而你总有一个合理的原因
you've always had a good reason.
但这次...  纯粹是白白流血
But this... it's just blood lost.
你这是在葬送一个耗费了数年才得以实现的协议
You're destroying an agreement that took years to put together.
一个由凶手和骗子达成的协议吗
An agreement made by murderers and liars.
凶手
Murderers?
你才是杀人不眨眼的凶手吧
You're the one killing people in cold blood.
我杀的每个人都参与了今天的袭击
Everybody I took out had a hand in today's attack.
但是谁给你权力充当法官和陪审团
But who makes you judge and jury?
是泰勒总统
President Taylor,
就是当她同意掩盖真相的时候
when she agreed to the cover-up.
我本愿意接受通过法律途径裁决...
I would have accepted justice by law...
但你们这些人剥夺了我的这一正当途径
but that was taken away from me by people like you.
所以你说得对  我就是法官和陪审团
So you're right-- I am judge and jury.
现在  给我退后
Now, step back.
往车那边走
Start to move back towards the car.
我是在哈桑和蕾妮被杀后才参与进来的
Look, I came in after Hassan and Renee were killed.
这一切与我无关  你得相信我
I didn't have anything to do with that, you have to believe me.
给我跪下
Get on your knees!
求你了  鲍尔  我说的是实话
Please, Bauer, I'm telling you the truth.
我有个家  还有个女儿
I've got a family; I've got a little girl.
鲍尔  求你了...
Bauer, please...
求求你  别杀我
Please, don't kill me.
求你  求你了
Please. Please.
还是没人接
Still no answer.
你确定这是梅瑞狄斯·里德的号码吗
Are you sure this is Meredith Reed's number?
-她给我留的就这号  -那她为什么不接
- It's the number she gave me. - Then why isn't she answering?
我刚和盖里·克劳斯纳谈过了
I just spoked to Gary Klausner,
他是里德女士的编辑
Ms. Reed's editor.
他也不知道她的下落  也无法与她取得联系
He doesn't know where she is and has no way to reach her.
不过他好像急着挂电话
He seemed very anxious to get off the phone.
您要去哪
Where are you going?
泰勒总统和我将在不到一小时内
President Taylor and I are supposed to be sitting across the table
与尤里·萨瓦洛夫坐下会面了
from Yuri Suvarov in less than an hour.
如果他的政府与你父亲的死有关
If his government was involved in murdering your father,
那泰勒总统必须得知道
President Taylor needs to know.
伴随奥马·哈桑的死
Following the death of Omar Hassan,
据传萨瓦洛夫总统曾一度对和谈
President Suvarov was reportedly pessimistic
能否继续持悲观态度
about the viability of the peace treaty.
但关于俄罗斯方面要退出和谈的谣言
But rumors of a Russian withdrawal
很快就被白宫方面澄清
were soon dismissed by the White House,
萨瓦洛夫总统将即刻抵达联合国总部
and President Suvarov is expected to arrive at the U.N. Shortly.
请进
Yes?
请恕打扰  总统阁下
Excuse me, Madam President.
是达莉亚·哈桑
It's Dalia Hassan.
我会给她回电的
I'll have to call her back.
她就在外面  总统阁下
She's outside, ma'am.
她说事情很紧急
She says it's urgent.
让她进来
Send her in.
总统阁下  请原谅
Madam President, forgive me.
我刚听到了让我非常不安的消息
I have just heard something that is very disturbing.
您听到了什么
What did you hear?
俄罗斯政府
That the Russian government,
或者说是俄罗斯政府内部的人
or people within the Russian government,
与我丈夫的死有关
were involved in the murder of my husband.
您从哪听到的
Where did you hear this?
我女儿接到了一个电话
My daughter received a phone call
来自梅瑞狄斯·里德  就是那个记者
from the journalist, Meredith Reed.
您亲自和她谈过吗
Have you spoken with her yourself?
没有
No.
我试过了一切方法
I've tried everything,
但还是无法与她取得联系
but I've been unable to reach her.
我来这是寻求您的帮助  帮我找寻里德小姐
I came here to ask for your help finding Miss Reed.
我要知道她所说的是否属实
I need to know if there is any truth in what she said.
达莉亚  我们也听到过
Dalia, we heard a rumor
关于俄罗斯牵涉其中的一个谣言
about the Russians being involved as well.
而您却没有告诉我
And you didn't tell me?
没有  因为我们调查过了
No. Because we looked into it
发现这纯属谣言
and found that there was nothing backing it up.
只是个轻率的指控罢了
It was just a frivolous accusation.
且不说她其他方面的是非
Whatever else she may be,
梅瑞狄斯·里德可不是个轻率的人
Meredith Reed is not a frivolous woman.
她来找我
She came to me,
明知道我完全有理由来质疑她
someone she knew would have every reason to doubt her.
达莉亚
Dalia...
我知道你需要答案
I know that you want answers...
但再过不到一小时  我们就要签署和平协议了
but we are signing the agreement in less than an hour.
总统阁下  我想我说得不够清楚
Madam President, I feel like you're not listening to me.
在我和这个可能是我杀夫凶手的人签署协议前
Before I sign a treaty with people who may have murdered my husband,
必须得帮我找到这个女人
I need help finding this woman.
拜托了
Please.
我会在我们剩余的时间内尽全力去找的
I will do the best I can in the time that we have left.
我想我说得还不够清楚
I don't think I'm making myself clear.
在我没弄清她所言是否属实之前
Until I determine if her allegations are true,
我是不会签署这份协议的
I will not sign this treaty.
达莉亚
Dalia...
拜托  别意气用事
please, be reasonable.
这就是我的立场  总统阁下
This is my position, Madam President.
我意已决
I will not change my mind.
那么你...  让我没得选择
Then you... You leave me no choice.
是我下令逮捕了梅瑞狄斯·里德
I had Meredith Reed arrested.
为什么
Why?
因为她所说的话破坏性太强了
Because her allegations would be too damaging.
这也说不通啊
That doesn't make any sense.
就算她所言非实  您也不会逮捕她吧
You wouldn't arrest someone for making false allegations.
除非她说的是真的
Unless they aren't false.
你早就知道了
You knew!
你早就知道俄罗斯政府是杀我丈夫的幕后黑手
You knew the Russians were behind my husband's death,
而你却缄口不言
and you said nothing?!
达莉亚
Dalia,
我非常抱歉
I am so sorry.
当时的处境根本让我没得选择
It-it was an im-impossible situation.
我是在设法保护你
I was trying to protect you.
保护我
Protect me?
你背叛了我
You betrayed me!
达莉亚  我们即将完成数代人的心血
Dalia, we are about to complete the most important
实现举世瞩目的外交壮举
diplomatic action in generations.
您丈夫为了保住这一协议牺牲了自己的生命...
Your husband sacrificed his life to preserve this treaty...
你还有脸提起我丈夫
How dare you invoke my husband!
他还活着的话  绝无可能容忍此事
He never would have stood for this!
之所以有这个协议是因为他信任你
This treaty happened because he trusted you.
即便是当时我迫切地想回家哀悼他
And even though every fiber in my being wanted to go home and grieve,
我还是选择继续  因为我信任你
I carried on because I trusted you.
但我再也不会信任你了
But not anymore.
我是绝对不会
I will not make peace
与谋杀我丈夫的人和谈  包括你
with the people who murdered my husband. Or with you.
不会再有什么和平协议
There will be no agreement.
我会向联合国提交一份正式的控诉
I will be entering a formal complaint with the United Nations,
要求你释放里德女士
demanding that you release Ms. Reed,
并公开一切你隐瞒我
and disclose whatever evidence you've kept from me
和世人的证据
and from the rest of the world!
站住
Stop!
一小时内  你会和我并肩出现在会议中心
In one hour, you will stand beside me in the council chamber,
你将签署你丈夫之前与我达成的和平协议
and you will sign the treaty your husband and I agreed to.
-做梦  -你会签的
- I will not! - You will!
因为如果你不签
Because if you don't,
我方政府将公开确凿而有力的证据
my administration will disclose hard, indisputable evidence
贵国情报部门的间谍
that agents inside your intelligence service
企图在我国领土引爆核弹
attempted to detonate a nuclear device on our soil,
这让我有一切所需的正当理由
which will give me all the justification I need
对伊斯兰共和国进行报复性打击
to retaliate against the IRK
打击将倾注美军全部军力
with the full force of the American military.
这将让贵国在数十年内无法恢复
It will be decades before your country recovers.
不过我们不必非要走到那一步
But it doesn't need to come to that.
你只需签署协议
All you have to do is sign the agreement.
达莉亚
Dalia?!
先是我丈夫遇刺身亡
First they murder my husband,
现在这个欺骗了我的女人又来威胁我的国家
and now this woman who has lied to me is threatening my country!
我现在一筹莫展  总统阁下
I don't see a way out of this, Madam President.
我们可以向全世界揭露这些俄罗斯杂种干的好事
We can tell the world what these Russian bastards did,
而泰勒总统又是怎样护着他们的
and how President Taylor protected them.
我们可以直接上诉海牙国际法庭
We can take our case directly to The Hague.
罪名根本不成立
There is no case.
我们的任何一项指控都没有证据支持
No proof to support any of these accusations.
更重要的是
More important,
还要考虑泰勒总统对我国的威胁
there are President Taylor's threats to consider.
我们不能忽略这些因素
We cannot dismiss them.
我们的军队能保护我们不受侵犯
Our military can protect us from incursion.
如有必要  我们可以重启核子计划
And if necessary, we can reactivate our nuclear program!
这正中您丈夫敌人的下怀
Giving your husband's enemies exactly what they wanted in the first place.
也给了她更充足的借口
In addition to providing her with even more of an excuse
先行对我国发动军事打击
to launch a preemptive military strike against us.
我才不管泰勒说过什么  她没那胆子
I don't care what President Taylor said; she wouldn't dare.
您真的能冒那个险吗
Can you really take that chance?
请讲
Yes?
谢谢
Thank you.
尤里·萨瓦洛夫的代表团随时都会达到
Yuri Suvarov's delegation will be arriving any moment.
泰勒总统希望您去迎接他
President Taylor is expecting you there to greet him.
奥迪斯探员
Agent Ortiz?
我刚和阿洛通过话
I just spoke with Arlo.
他刚获得了杰克的脸部识别匹配图
He got a facial recognition hit on Jack.
在哪里
Where?
就在我们的警戒范围内
Inside our perimeter.
他就在这里  科尔
He's here, Cole.
他很谨慎  躲过了所有监控探头
He's been careful to avoid all the security cameras,
不过阿洛发现了这个
but Arlo found this.
是从联合国街对面的哈特大厦第22层拍到的
It's from the 22nd floor of the Hart Building across the street from the U.N.
软件系统识别出了他在玻璃中的样子
The software picked up his reflection.
他怎么进到大厦里去的
How did he get into the building?
根据记录  过去二十分钟内
According to the logs, the only person that entered the building
唯一进入那栋大厦的是皮勒
within the past 20 minutes was Pillar.
杰克一定已挟持了他
Jack must have taken him hostage.
透过大厦东边的窗户
The windows on the east side of the building
让他能清楚地看到演讲台
give him a clean line of sight down onto the podium.
我去找他
I'm going to go find him.
我和你一起去
I'm going with you.
不行
You can't.
这样只会燃起"战火"
It would just cause a fight.
杰克只愿意听我的劝
I'm the only one that Jack will listen to.
如果他不听你的呢
And what if he doesn't?
给我二十分钟
Give me 20 minutes.
如果还没有我的消息
If you don't hear from me,
我们就按原计划进行
we'll follow through with our plan.
启动对杰克的警报  并保护萨瓦洛夫
Sound the alarm about Jack and secure Suvarov.
就二十分钟
20 minutes.
-好  -别关掉通讯器
- Okay. - And keep your comm open.
-我要掌握一切动态  -不行
- I want to know what's going on. - I can't.
反恐组正监控所有频率
CTU is monitoring all frequencies.
这样太冒险了
It's too risky.
好吧
All right.
那最起码带上这个
At least take this.
-谢谢  -要多加小心
- Thanks. - Be careful.
奥布赖恩去哪了
Where's O'Brian headed?
她要再最后清查一下警戒区
She's running a last-minute perimeter sweep.
她一个人干吗
By herself?
保持与萨瓦洛夫的保镖实时通讯和图像传输畅通
Keep a real-time uplink open with Suvarov's security people.
一切开始运作了就通知我
Let me know when it's up and running.
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.
好
Okay.
就我所记得的
As long as I can remember,
过去每次我不得已和你谈话
every time I've had to talk to you,
似乎总是因各种原因
it seems, for one reason or another,
我总先以抱歉作为开场白
I've started out by telling you how sorry I am.
但今天我不会对你那么说了
I'm not going to do that to you now.
你将听到关于我今天行为的各种版本的说法
You're going to hear a lot of stories about what I've done today.
有些可能是事实
Some of them may even be true.
可没有人  我是说除我之外
But no one, and I mean no one
没人能告诉你  我为何那么干的原因
can tell you why I did what I did except for me.
今天很多好人丧生了
And a lot of good people died today.
不止是哈桑总统
Not just President Hassan.
反恐组的探员们  其他执法机构的工作人员们
Operatives from CTU, members of other law enforcement agencies.
还有蕾妮·沃克
Renee Walker.
她和我关系非常亲密
Who I was very close to.
请讲
Yes?
谢谢
Thank you.
萨瓦洛夫总统的车队快到了
President Suvarov's motorcade has just rounded the corner.
此事通知哈桑夫人了吗
Was Mrs. Hassan notified of his arrival?
应该通知了  阁下
I believe so, ma'am.
到底通知了没  蒂姆
Yes or no, Tim? Which is it?
她到底来还是不来
Is she coming or not?
她有什么理由不来
Why wouldn't she be?
泰勒总统  我们齐聚一堂
President Taylor, that we are all here together
是您坚持不懈的成果
is a tribute to your persistence.
哈桑夫人  请节哀
Mrs. Hassan, I am sorry for your loss.
我非常欣赏您的丈夫
I admired your husband very much.
我们该上楼参加记者招待会了
We're wanted upstairs for the press conference.
那是当然
Yes, of course.
总统阁下
Mr. President.
达莉亚  我知道你现在很不好受
Dalia, I know that this is very difficult for you.
我们彼此间没什么好说的了
There is nothing left for either of us to say,
总统阁下
Madam President.
我是克罗伊·奥布赖恩  反恐组主管
Chloe O'Brian, Director of CTU.
是  长官
Yes, ma'am.
这是您要求的万能钥匙和大厦结构图
Master key and building schematics you requested.
谢谢
Thank you.
下午好  各位与会代表
Good afternoon, fellow delegates
及新闻界的女士们先生们
and ladies and gentlemen of the press.
在这条我们同舟共济的漫长而荆棘丛生的道路上
The last 24 hours have been the most difficult in this
我们经历了无比艰难的24小时
long and challenging road that we've all traveled together
才迎来了这一时刻
to reach this moment.
此刻  全世界的目光都聚焦到
Now, the eyes of the entire world are looking
站在我身边的这些领袖们身上
to the leaders standing here with me now,
准备着迎来一个
ready to usher in a new era of
透明  诚实  互信的新纪元
transparency, honesty and trust.
泰勒总统  哈桑总统
President Taylor, President Hassan
萨瓦洛夫总统都为世界和平
President Suvarov have each risen
成功地应对了这一挑战
to this challenge for the sake of world peace.
他们一同创定的这份协议
And the treaty that they have created together
代表着他们无畏努力所取得的高峰
represents the culmination of their courageous efforts.
伯克探员
Agent Burke?
-长官  -你去召集一支十人小队
- Sir. - I need you to assemble a ten-man squad
将他们部署在C-7区
and deploy them to Sector C-7.
是哈特大厦吗  长官  已经有人上岗了
The Hart Building, sir? We already have men on post there.
如果那条长廊任一地点产生威胁
Not nearly enough if there's a threat
这些人手远远不够用
anywhere along that corridor.
让你的手下待在大厦外
Keep your men outside the building
直到你接到其它命令
until you hear otherwise.
你来这干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
你不必杀死萨瓦洛夫  还有其它法子
You don't have to kill Suvarov. There's another way.
还有谁知道我在这里
Who else knows where I am?
-请听我说  -还有谁知道
- Please listen. - Who else knows?!
科尔和阿洛
Cole and Arlo.
如果我不在十分钟内把你带出去
If I don't get you out of here in ten minutes,
科尔会派出所有探员
Cole's gonna send in every agent we have.
杰克  他们会置你于死地
Jack, they're going to kill you.
现行指令要求对你格杀勿论
There's a standing order to shoot you on sight.
我不能坐视不管
I couldn't let that happen.
你不该来找我
You shouldn't have come after me.
你是我朋友
You're my friend.
我别无选择
I didn't have a choice.
我也一样
Neither do I.
别挣扎
Don't fight it.
杰森  你在看电视吗
Jason, you watching this?
杰森
Jason?
我正将556口径步枪对准你的脑袋
I have a five-five-six rifle pointed straight at your head.
子弹射速每秒2900英尺
The bullet travels 2,900 feet per second.
你胆敢动一下  就必死无疑
If you try and move, you're a dead man.
所以你得照我说的做
Which means you need to do exactly what I say.
明白吗
Do you understand?
杰克  我已对你和盘托出了
Uh, Jack, I told you everything I know.
你以为我会相信你吗
And you thought I believed you?
除了我  只有诺瓦科维奇知道
And aside from me, Novakovich was the only one
是萨瓦洛夫在幕后操控
who knew that Suvarov was calling the shots.
你想怎么样
What do you want?
我想让你给萨瓦洛夫总统打个电话
I want you to call President Suvarov
就去你现在所在地见你
as soon as the press conference is over.
我该怎么跟他讲
What am I supposed to tell him?
换个方式  试试讲讲真相
Try the truth for a change.
告诉他  你掌握了事关他性命之危的可靠情报
Tell him you've got credible intelligence about a threat to his life.